♪An early or a perfect or a destined love♪
♪ حب مبكر أو كامل أو مقدر ♪
♪It may start out like a prank♪
قد تبدأ مثل المزحة
♪Love is so confusing♪
الحب محير جدا ♪
♪An isolated frozen island melts♪
جزيرة مجمدة معزولة تذوب
♪And travels to the end of the universe♪
ويسافر إلى نهاية الكون ♪
♪What words shall I use to describe♪
ما هي الكلمات التي يجب أن أستخدمها لوصف ♪
♪The long-awaited embrace♪
العناق الذي طال انتظاره ♪
♪An isolated frozen island melts♪
جزيرة مجمدة معزولة تذوب
♪My breathing becomes warmer♪
تنفسي يصبح أكثر دفئًا ♪
♪And travels to the end of the universe♪
ويسافر إلى نهاية الكون ♪
♪What words shall I use to describe♪
ما هي الكلمات التي يجب أن أستخدمها لوصف ♪
♪The long-awaited embrace♪
العناق الذي طال انتظاره ♪
♪An isolated frozen island melts♪
جزيرة مجمدة معزولة تذوب
♪My breathing becomes warmer♪
تنفسي يصبح أكثر دفئًا ♪
♪An isolated island♪
♪ جزيرة معزولة ♪
=Dear Little Mermaid=
= عزيزتي ليتل ميرميد =
=Episode 6=
= الحلقة 6 =
So many problems?
الكثير من المشاكل؟
I can't believe it.
لا أصدق ذلك.
Never mind.
لا تهتم.
Let's fight for it.
دعونا نقاتل من أجل ذلك.
I'll break down the problems
سوف أقوم بتفصيل المشاكل
and find the solutions together.
وإيجاد الحلول معًا.
Let's send over the answers early tomorrow morning.
دعنا نرسل الإجابات في وقت مبكر من صباح الغد.
♪An early or a perfect or a destined love♪
♪ حب مبكر أو كامل أو مقدر ♪
♪It may start out like a prank♪
قد تبدأ مثل المزحة
♪Love is so confusing♪
الحب محير جدا ♪
Xuezhou,
Xuezhou ،
want more?
تريد المزيد؟
No need.
لا حاجة.
It's enough.
هذا يكفى.
Cheers!
هتافات!
♪An isolated frozen island melts♪
جزيرة مجمدة معزولة تذوب
♪And travels to the end of the universe♪
ويسافر إلى نهاية الكون ♪
♪What words shall I use to describe♪
ما هي الكلمات التي يجب أن أستخدمها لوصف ♪
♪The long-awaited embrace♪
العناق الذي طال انتظاره ♪
♪An isolated frozen island melts♪
جزيرة مجمدة معزولة تذوب
♪My breathing becomes warmer♪
تنفسي يصبح أكثر دفئًا ♪
(Bubaiqi Plan)
(خطة بوبيقي)
I'll make a call first.
سأجري مكالمة أولا.
Take a rest. You've worked hard.
خذ راحة.  لقد عملت بجد.
You've also worked hard, Xuezhou.
لقد عملت بجد أيضًا يا Xuezhou.
(Enter password)
(أدخل كلمة المرور)
(I look forward to our date tonight.)
(إنني أتطلع إلى موعدنا الليلة.)
(Delete)﻿
(حذف)
Boss,
رئيس،
you're awake.
انت مستيقظ.
What's the matter?
ما الأمر؟
What is the time now?
ما هو الوقت الأن؟
It's right after 5:30 pm.
إنه الحق بعد الساعة 5:30 مساءً.
5:30 pm?
5:30 مساءا؟
Where is Xuezhou?
أين Xuezhou؟
She's over there.
إنها هناك.
I feel uneasy.
أشعر بعدم الارتياح.
Can you amend this part again?
هل يمكنك تعديل هذا الجزء مرة أخرى؟
This part?
هذا الجزء؟
Xuezhou,
Xuezhou ،
is there something wrong?
هل هناك شيء خاطيء؟
Su Lun's latest constructive feedback
أحدث تعليقات Su Lun البناءة
is very different from your comic theme.
يختلف تمامًا عن موضوعك الهزلي.
Manager Xia wants us
مدير شيا يريدنا
to come up with a plan
للتوصل إلى خطة
that will satisfy Su Lun as soon as possible
من شأنها أن ترضي Su Lun في أقرب وقت ممكن
and seal this project.
وختم هذا المشروع.
How come it turns out like this?
كيف اتضح مثل هذا؟
I won't believe it.
لن أصدق ذلك.
Give it another go.
جربها مرة أخرى.
I'm sure I can take on this big piece of the pie.
أنا متأكد من أنني أستطيع أخذ هذه القطعة الكبيرة من الكعكة.
Everybody!
الجميع!
Let's fight for it!
دعونا نقاتل من أجل ذلك!
Go!
يذهب!
Look at the color of this part.
انظر إلى لون هذا الجزء.
Make it...
أصنعها...
Sir, this way please.
سيدي ، بهذه الطريقة من فضلك.
Okay. Thank you.
تمام.  شكرًا لك.
Sir, here's your water.
سيدي ، ها هي مياهك.
Apply the commonly used
ضعي المستحضر الشائع الاستخدام
color blocks here. Got it?
كتل ملونة هنا.  فهمتك؟
Okay.
تمام.
Come, let me take a look.
تعال ، دعني ألقي نظرة.
(Don't be late. Don't stand me up.)
(لا تتأخر. لا تقف معي).
(I'm busy with work.)
(أنا مشغول بالعمل.)
(I'll try my best to finish it earlier.)
(سأبذل قصارى جهدي لإنهائه في وقت سابق.)
(Okay. I'll wait for you.)
(حسنًا ، سأنتظرك.)
Boss,
رئيس،
I encountered some problems.
واجهت بعض المشاكل.
Can you come and take a look?
هل يمكنك المجيء وإلقاء نظرة؟
Xuezhou,
Xuezhou ،
I have something important now.
لدي شيء مهم الآن.
I need to leave for a while.
أنا بحاجة إلى المغادرة لفترة من الوقت.
What's way more important
ما هي الطريقة الأكثر أهمية
than the job on hand?
من العمل في متناول اليد؟
It's... I...
إنه ساي...
I'm going to find Bai Qijia and ask for a clean break.
سأعثر على باي تشي جيا وأطلب استراحة نظيفة.
A clean break?
استراحة نظيفة؟
You've finally come to your senses
لقد وصلت أخيرًا إلى حواسك
and decided to stay away from this scumbag.
وقررت الابتعاد عن هذا الحثالة.
He's having an affair with his ex-girlfriend.
لديه علاقة غرامية مع صديقته السابقة.
Yet, he came to pester you. What kind of man is he?
ومع ذلك ، جاء ليضايقك.  أي نوع من الرجل هو؟
Well, this matter is a little complicated.
حسنًا ، هذا الأمر معقد بعض الشيء.
But his ex-girlfriend...
لكن صديقته السابقة ...
isn't wrong either.
ليس خطأ أيضا.
But it's better to get it resolved.
لكن من الأفضل حلها.
Go. I understand you well.
يذهب.  انا افهمك جيدا.
Go and battle with him.
اذهب وحارب معه.
Let me tell you.
دعني أخبرك.
Don't lose your imposing manner.
لا تفقد أسلوبك المهيب.
Understood?
فهمت؟
Your imposing manner.
أسلوبك المهيب.
Go on.
تابع.
I will.
أنا سوف.
Fighting!
قتال!
(Hangover)
(دوار من اثر الخمرة)
Excuse me. May I know
اعذرني.  هل لي أن أعلم
if you've seen
إذا رأيت
a gentleman waiting for someone here?
رجل محترم ينتظر شخص ما هنا؟
I think there was one.
أعتقد أنه كان هناك واحد.
He has waited for a long time. He just left.
لقد انتظر طويلا.  لقد غادر للتو.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
You're welcome.
على الرحب والسعة.
Qin Ge.
تشين قه.
(Department of Immunology)
(قسم المناعة)
Xuezhou, over here.
Xuezhou ، هنا.
Qin Ge.
تشين قه.
Miss, how is she?
انسة كيف حالها
Don't worry. Her fever has subsided.
لا تقلق.  خفت حمىها.
Her heart rate has also stabilized.
كما استقر معدل ضربات قلبها.
But for safety reasons,
ولكن لأسباب تتعلق بالسلامة ،
she needs to stay for a few days for observation.
تحتاج إلى البقاء لبضعة أيام للمراقبة.
Miss,
يغيب،
my friend has a history of systemic lupus erythematosus.
صديقي لديه تاريخ من الذئبة الحمامية الجهازية.
Could her loss of consciousness be related...
هل يمكن أن يرتبط فقدانها للوعي ...
Don't worry. It was fatigue
لا تقلق.  كان التعب
and the rapid heartbeat induced by low blood sugar
وسرعة ضربات القلب الناجم عن انخفاض نسبة السكر في الدم
that had caused the unconsciousness.
الذي تسبب في فقدان الوعي.
And also due to body heat and fever symptoms.
وأيضًا بسبب حرارة الجسم وأعراض الحمى.
Fortunately, Dr. Bai brought her over in time
لحسن الحظ ، أحضرها الدكتور باي في الوقت المناسب
that her condition did not trigger other complications.
أن حالتها لم تسبب مضاعفات أخرى.
You all have come.
لقد أتيتم جميعًا.
Bai Qijia, come out with me.
باي Qijia ، تعال معي.
Bai Qijia, I'll cut to the chase.
باي Qijia ، سوف أقطع المطاردة.
I don't care what your relationship is
لا يهمني ما هي علاقتك
with your ex-girlfriend.
مع صديقتك السابقة.
From now on,
من الان فصاعدا،
please stay away from Qin Ge.
يرجى الابتعاد عن Qin Ge.
If I see you
اذا انا اراك
being entangled between two ladies again,
تتشابك بين سيدتين مرة أخرى ،
I will...
أنا سوف...
I'm so sorry about what happened to Qin Ge.
أنا آسف جدًا لما حدث لـ Qin Ge.
It's my fault that I've failed to notice her illness earlier.
إنه خطأي أنني فشلت في ملاحظة مرضها في وقت سابق.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Why are you apologizing to me?
لماذا تعتذر لي؟
Didn't you always wonder
ألم تتساءل دائمًا
why Qin Ge stood you up eight years ago?
لماذا وقفك تشين قه قبل ثماني سنوات؟
Let me tell you.
دعني أخبرك.
It was because she had systemic lupus erythematosus.
كان ذلك بسبب إصابتها بالذئبة الحمامية الجهازية.
It was because she almost died!
كان ذلك لأنها كادت أن تموت!
That's enough, Xuezhou.
هذا يكفي يا Xuezhou.
There's no point telling him all these.
ليس هناك فائدة من إخباره بكل هذا.
Bai Qijia, let me tell you.
باي Qijia ، دعني أخبرك.
You don't deserve to make any promises with Qin Ge.
أنت لا تستحق أن تقدم أي وعود مع Qin Ge.
Men like you
رجال مثلك
deserve to be stood up.
تستحق أن تنهض.
You deserve it.
تستحقها.
Xuezhou,
Xuezhou ،
go in and stay by Qin Ge's side.
ادخل وابق بجانب Qin Ge.
Leave this matter to me.
اترك هذا الأمر لي.
I'll handle it.
أنا التعامل معها.
Dr. Bai,
دكتور.  باي ،
let's go out and talk.
دعنا نخرج ونتحدث.
Didn't you always want to know
ألا تريد دائمًا أن تعرف
what happened to Qin Ge?
ماذا حدث لـ Qin Ge؟
I'll tell you everything then.
سأخبرك بكل شيء بعد ذلك.
Three years ago,
منذ ثلاثة أعوام،
when I joined Bai Qi Studio,
عندما انضممت إلى استوديو Bai Qi ،
Qin Ge solemnly told me
قال لي تشين قه رسميًا
that she was diagnosed with hereditary systemic lupus erythematosus.
أنه تم تشخيص إصابتها بالذئبة الحمامية الجهازية الوراثية.
If it's not under control in severe cases,
إذا لم يكن تحت السيطرة في الحالات الشديدة ،
she'll lose her life at any moment.
ستفقد حياتها في أي لحظة.
She even joked
حتى أنها مازحت
that if...
هذا لو...
She wanted me to carry on her legacy
أرادت مني الاستمرار في إرثها
and inherit her assets.
وترث أصولها.
I didn't expect that this was why
لم أكن أتوقع أن هذا هو السبب
she didn't bid me farewell back then.
لم تودعني في ذلك الوقت.
But why didn't she
لكن لماذا لم تفعل ذلك
tell me personally?
اخبرني شخصيا؟
Whenever she encounters problems, Qin Ge prefers
عندما تواجه مشاكل ، تفضل Qin Ge
to shoulder them alone.
لتحملهم وحدهم.
She doesn't want to tell any outsiders
إنها لا تريد إخبار أي غرباء
about her personal matters.
عن شؤونها الشخصية.
Of course, except for Xuezhou and me,
بالطبع ، باستثناء Xuezhou وأنا ،
no one else knows about her secret.
لا أحد يعرف سرها.
I regretted
ندمت
that I wasn't by her side
أنني لم أكن بجانبها
when she needed me most.
عندما كانت في أمس الحاجة إلي.
I'll definitely treat her better in the future.
بالتأكيد سأعاملها بشكل أفضل في المستقبل.
I'll make it up to her
سوف أعوضها لها
and won't let her get hurt.
ولن تدعها تتأذى.
Have you ever cared about
هل اهتممت من قبل
why she's unwilling to tell others?
لماذا لا ترغب في إخبار الآخرين؟
Let me tell you.
دعني أخبرك.
Qin Ge just wants to live a peaceful
Qin Ge يريد فقط أن يعيش في سلام
and happy life.
وحياة سعيدة.
She doesn't want to carry
هي لا تريد أن تحمل
the "patient" label forever.
علامة "المريض" إلى الأبد.
She also doesn't want to become
هي أيضًا لا تريد أن تصبح
a bird trapped in the cage.
عصفور محاصر في القفص.
Are you sure
هل أنت واثق
you understand her well?
هل تفهمها جيدا
I said
انا قلت
Qin Ge needs
يحتاج تشين قه
a peaceful life so she can focus on creating.
حياة سلمية حتى تتمكن من التركيز على الإبداع.
She doesn't need any outsiders to appear suddenly
إنها لا تحتاج إلى أي غرباء ليظهروا فجأة
and tell her what to do.
وأخبرها ماذا تفعل.
Do you mean
هل تعني
you're the most suitable man for Qin Ge?
أنت الرجل الأنسب لـ Qin Ge؟
Dr. Bai,
دكتور.  باي ،
when I first met you,
عندما التقيت لأول مرة لك،
I wanted to tell you
اردت ان اخبرك
that you shouldn't come back again
أنه لا يجب عليك العودة مرة أخرى
after you left eight years ago.
بعد مغادرتك قبل ثماني سنوات.
Qin Ge is no longer
Qin Ge لم يعد
the single-minded girl she used to be.
الفتاة ذات التفكير الواحد التي اعتادت أن تكون.
She now has a new life of her own.
لديها الآن حياة جديدة خاصة بها.
Please stop disturbing her.
من فضلك توقف عن إزعاجها.
Let's take another look later.
لنلقي نظرة أخرى لاحقًا.
Okay.
تمام.
Isn't that Procrastinator Bai?
أليس هذا المماطل باي؟
Didn't he change shifts today and already leave?
ألم يغير الورديات اليوم وغادر بالفعل؟
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
I think I saw Dr. Bai
أعتقد أنني رأيت الدكتور باي
sent a female patient to the emergency room just now.
أرسل مريضة إلى غرفة الطوارئ الآن.
A female patient?
مريضة؟
It's all my fault.
هذا كله خطأي.
I shouldn't have let you meet him.
لا يجب أن أتركك تقابله.
It's my fault for not taking good care of you.
إنه خطأي لأنني لم أعتني بك جيدًا.
Min, you go home first.
مين ، أنت تذهب إلى المنزل أولاً.
I'll stay by her side tonight.
سأبقى بجانبها الليلة.
Xuezhou?
Xuezhou؟
Why are you crying?
لماذا تبكين
What are you doing here?
ما الذي تفعله هنا؟
Get out.
اخرج.
I came to see Qin Ge.
جئت لرؤية تشين قه.
What happened? Why is she admitted to the Department of Immunology?
ماذا حدث؟  لماذا تم قبولها في قسم المناعة؟
Come out with me.
تعال معي.
Lu Tian, let me tell you.
لو تيان ، دعني أخبرك.
If you're thinking of colluding with Bai Qijia,
إذا كنت تفكر في التواطؤ مع باي كي جيا ،
I'll beat you up every time I see you.
سأضربك في كل مرة أراك فيها.
Wait.
انتظر.
Don't talk to yourself and walk away after that.
لا تتحدث مع نفسك وابتعد بعد ذلك.
What is this?
ما هذا؟
What do you mean by "colluding with Bai Qijia?"
ماذا تقصد ب "التواطؤ مع باي قيجيا"؟
Stop pretending.
كف عن التظاهر.
You don't know that Bai Qijia
أنت لا تعرف أن باي Qijia
still pesters Qin Ge even after he reconciled with his ex-girlfriend?
لا يزال يضايق تشين قه حتى بعد أن تصالح مع صديقته السابقة؟
Aren't you planning to speak for him?
ألا تخطط للتحدث نيابة عنه؟
I...
أنا...
Whatever.
ايا كان.
Procrastinator Bai doesn't have an ex-girlfriend.
المماطلة باي ليس لديها صديقة سابقة.
The girl you saw at the private cinema
الفتاة التي رأيتها في السينما الخاصة
was Qin Ge.
كان Qin Ge.
And the girl with a shielded face you saw
والفتاة ذات الوجه المحجوب التي رأيتموها
on his Moments was also Qin Ge.
في لحظاته كان أيضًا Qin Ge.
If I lie to you again this time,
إذا كذبت عليك مرة أخرى هذه المرة ،
I'll be alone forever.
سأكون وحدي إلى الأبد.
It was they who didn't want you to know.
إنهم هم الذين لا يريدونك أن تعرف.
So I told a small lie.
فقلت كذبة صغيرة.
Lu Tian,
لو تيان ،
stop running!
توقف عن الركض!
(She was diagnosed with hereditary systemic lupus erythematosus.)
(تم تشخيص إصابتها بالذئبة الحمامية الجهازية الوراثية.)
(If it's not under control in severe cases,)
(إذا لم يكن تحت السيطرة في الحالات الشديدة ،)
(she'll lose her life at any moment.)
(ستفقد حياتها في أي لحظة).
I remember you liked the sun very much before.
أتذكر أنك أحببت الشمس كثيرًا من قبل.
When we reach middle age, we need to protect ourselves against aging.
عندما نصل إلى منتصف العمر ، نحتاج إلى حماية أنفسنا من الشيخوخة.
It should start with protecting ourselves against the ultraviolet rays.
يجب أن نبدأ بحماية أنفسنا من الأشعة فوق البنفسجية.
Eat.
تأكل.
Wasn't seafood your favorite?
ألم تكن المأكولات البحرية المفضلة لديك؟
My taste has changed.
لقد تغير ذوقي.
Miss Bai Qi, you've covered yourself up already.
آنسة باي تشي ، لقد غطيت نفسك بالفعل.
You're still afraid of the light?
هل مازلت تخاف من الضوء؟
You're clueless. Actually,
أنت جاهل.  في الحقيقة،
I've turned into a vampire.
لقد تحولت إلى مصاص دماء.
I can't carry on.
لا أستطيع الاستمرار.
-Slow down. -I can't carry on.
-ابطئ.  -لا يمكنني الاستمرار.
I can't walk anymore. My legs are about to break.
لا أستطيع المشي بعد الآن.  ساقي على وشك الكسر.
Have you ever cared about
هل اهتممت من قبل
why she's unwilling to tell others?
لماذا لا ترغب في إخبار الآخرين؟
(Qin Ge just wants to live a peaceful)
(يريد Qin Ge فقط أن يعيش في سلام)
(and happy life.)
(وحياة سعيدة.)
(She doesn't want to carry)
(هي لا تريد أن تحمل)
(the "patient" label forever.)
(علامة "المريض" إلى الأبد).
You're not entirely wrong.
أنت لست مخطئا تماما.
(Conversation Room) After I reunited with Qin Ge,
(غرفة المحادثة) بعد أن اجتمعت مع Qin Ge ،
I didn't show her enough care.
لم أُظهر لها الرعاية الكافية.
So I'm trying my best to make it up to her.
لذلك أحاول بذل قصارى جهدي لتعويضها.
From tonight onwards, let me look after her.
من الليلة فصاعدًا ، دعني أعتني بها.
I'm a doctor.
أنا طبيب.
I know how to deal with any problems better.
أعرف كيف أتعامل مع أي مشاكل بشكل أفضل.
Lu Tian has explained about your ex-girlfriend
أوضح لو تيان عن صديقتك السابقة
clearly to me.
بوضوح بالنسبة لي.
I'm sorry for having misunderstood you.
أنا آسف لأنني أسأت فهمك.
I've gone too far.
لقد ذهبت بعيدا.
Don't take it to heart.
لا تأخذ الأمر على محمل الجد.
But it's better that I take care of Qin Ge instead.
لكن من الأفضل أن أعتني بـ Qin Ge بدلاً من ذلك.
After all, I'm more experienced than you.
بعد كل شيء ، أنا أكثر خبرة منك.
I'm not as good as you all in terms of experience.
أنا لست جيدًا مثلكم جميعًا من حيث الخبرة.
But please give me
لكن من فضلك أعطني
another chance
فرصة أخرى
to gradually make up
للتعويض تدريجيا
for my lack of company and care in the past eight years.
لافتقاري إلى الشركة والرعاية في السنوات الثماني الماضية.
Xuezhou,
Xuezhou ،
why did you agree to let Bai Qijia take care of Boss?
لماذا وافقت على ترك باي Qijia يعتني بالرئيس؟
I had a feeling
كان لدي شعور
that Qin Ge wanted him to stay by her side.
أن Qin Ge أراده أن يبقى بجانبها.
I knew you'd catch me.
كنت أعلم أنك ستمسك بي.
Close your eyes.
اغلق عينيك.
Don't look at me.
لا تنظر إلي.
I... Well...
أنا ... حسنًا ...
Close your eyes. I...
اغلق عينيك.  أنا...
It was merely an accident.
كان مجرد حادث.
I didn't know you were on this side of the wall.
لم أكن أعلم أنك كنت على هذا الجانب من الجدار.
I didn't mean to jump on you.
لم أقصد القفز عليك.
Well...
نحن سوف...
We met by chance.
التقينا بالصدفة.
Just treat it as if it never happened.
فقط تعامل مع الأمر كما لو أنه لم يحدث أبدًا.
Let's not remember each other.
دعونا لا نتذكر بعضنا البعض.
Okay.
تمام.
I'm going to leave now.
سأغادر الآن.
Don't open your eyes.
لا تفتح عينيك.
Open your eyes only after I've left.
افتح عينيك فقط بعد أن غادرت.
Wait. I'm still here.
انتظر.  انا مازلت هنا.
Firstly, let me introduce
أولا ، اسمحوا لي أن أقدم
the new transfer student in our class,
الطالب المنقول الجديد في صفنا ،
Bai Qijia. Let's welcome him.
باي قيجيا.  دعونا نرحب به.
What's the matter?
ما الأمر؟
Sir, I went to perform my class duty just now.
سيدي ، لقد ذهبت لأداء واجبي الطبقي الآن.
Let me introduce
دعني أقدم
the new transfer student in our class,
الطالب المنقول الجديد في صفنا ،
Bai Qijia.
باي قيجيا.
This is our class monitor.
هذا هو مراقب الفصل لدينا.
-You... -I know her name.
-أنت ... -أعرف اسمها.
She dropped her student card
أسقطت بطاقتها الطلابية
(Qingchuan Chengya High School. Qin Ge) outside the school compound just now.
(مدرسة Qingchuan Chengya الثانوية. Qin Ge) خارج مجمع المدرسة الآن.
Didn't you say you went to perform your class duty?
ألم تقل أنك ذهبت لأداء واجبك الدراسي؟
What kind of class duty do you need to settle outside the school?
ما نوع واجب الفصل الذي تحتاجه لتسوية خارج المدرسة؟
Did you go shopping for comic books again?
هل ذهبت للتسوق من أجل الكتب المصورة مرة أخرى؟
Sir, I'm sorry. I was wrong.
سيدي ، أنا آسف.  كنت مخطئا.
All right. All right. Stop talking about it.
حسنا.  حسنا.  توقف عن الحديث عنها.
Write your reading notes five times
اكتب ملاحظات القراءة الخاصة بك خمس مرات
and submit to me early tomorrow morning.
وتقدم لي في وقت مبكر من صباح الغد.
Go.
يذهب.
Come, that's your seat.
تعال ، هذا هو مقعدك.
Okay, my fellow students.
حسنًا ، زملائي الطلاب.
Before we begin our lesson,
قبل أن نبدأ الدرس ،
let us confirm the rotating assistant class monitor
دعونا نؤكد رصد فئة المساعد الدورية
of the month.
من الشهر.
Any volunteer?
أي متطوع؟
Speak, Qin Ge.
تحدث ، تشين قه.
Sir, I suggest that Bai Qijia
سيدي ، أقترح أن باي Qijia
be our assistant class monitor.
كن مراقب الفصل المساعد لدينا.
Sir, I...
سيدي ، أنا ...
Sir, Bai Qijia
سيدي ، باي قيجيا
isn't familiar with everyone here.
ليس على دراية بالجميع هنا.
If he becomes the assistant class monitor,
إذا أصبح مراقب الفصل المساعد ،
he'll get to know everyone very soon.
سيتعرف على الجميع قريبًا.
Please sit down.
من فضلك اجلس.
If no one else volunteers,
إذا لم يتطوع أي شخص آخر ،
then do anyone has any comments
ثم هل أي شخص لديه أي تعليقات
on Qin Ge's suggestion?
بناء على اقتراح تشين قه؟
All right then. Bai Qijia will be the assistant class monitor
حسنا إذا.  سيكون باي Qijia مراقب الفصل المساعد
of the month.
من الشهر.
I believe
أعتقد
our new classmate will surely give our class
بالتأكيد سيعطي زميلنا الجديد صفنا
a new look
نظرة جديدة
and bring our grades
وإحضار درجاتنا
to another level.
إلى مستوى آخر.
If there's no comment,
إذا لم يكن هناك تعليق ،
let's applaud to pass the motion.
دعونا نحيي لتمرير الاقتراح.
Qin Ge, you're the class monitor.
Qin Ge ، أنت مراقب الفصل.
He's new and clueless.
إنه جديد وجاهل.
Do show him the way.
أره الطريق.
Okay, Sir.
حسنا سيدي.
I'll look after him well.
سأعتني به جيدا.
Help me tell our classmates
ساعدني في إخبار زملائنا في الفصل
that I'm having a terrible stomachache.
أنني أعاني من آلام شديدة في المعدة.
Thank you!
شكرًا لك!
Assistant class monitor, this is the class attendance sheet.
مساعد مراقب الفصل ، هذه هي ورقة حضور الفصل.
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا لك.
Please be impartial and fair.
يرجى التحلي بالحياد والإنصاف.
Assistant class monitor!
مساعد مراقب الطبقة!
Please help me prepare
الرجاء مساعدتي في الاستعداد
tomorrow's class report.
تقرير الفصل الغد.
I have too much homework. I can't finish it.
لدي العديد من الواجبات المنزلية.  لا أستطيع أن أنهيها.
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا لك.
See you tomorrow!
أراك غدا!
Qijia,
Qijia ،
tell me the truth.
أخبرني الحقيقة.
Who prepared yesterday's class report?
من الذي أعد تقرير الفصل أمس؟
It was the class monitor who gave me
كان مراقب الفصل هو من أعطاني
her complete trust and support
ثقتها ودعمها الكاملين
and motivated me to finish it.
وحفزني على الانتهاء منه.
Why did I hear
لماذا سمعت
that she'd passed all the class duties to you just like that?
أنها قد نقلت جميع واجبات الفصل إليك بهذه الطريقة؟
Don't be afraid of her.
لا تخافوا منها.
She must get her own duties done herself.
يجب أن تقوم بواجباتها بنفسها.
You're our class's pacesetter of learning.
أنت رائد التعلم في صفنا.
You must not let anything affect your studies.
يجب ألا تدع أي شيء يؤثر على دراستك.
Okay.
تمام.
Got it, Sir.
فهمت يا سيدي.
You may leave.
يمكنك المغادرة.
Qin Ge, come in!
تشين قه ، تعال!
Bai Qijia.
باي قيجيا.
We have a class activity today.
لدينا نشاط صفي اليوم.
Please fill in for me at the library.
يرجى ملء بياناتي في المكتبة.
We'll fill in for you next time.
سنقوم بتعبئة البيانات لك في المرة القادمة.
Thanks.
شكرًا.
Bai Qijia!
باي قيجيا!
I've finally found you.
لقد وجدتك أخيرًا.
What's the matter? Why are you looking for me?
ما الأمر؟  لماذا تبحث عني؟
Why are you alone here?
لماذا انت وحدك هنا؟
Where are those from Class Three and Class One?
أين هؤلاء من الدرجة الثالثة والفئة الأولى؟
They have a class activity. They can't make it.
لديهم نشاط في الفصل.  لا يمكنهم فعل ذلك.
This is too much.
هذا كثير للغاية.
They've gone too far.
لقد ذهبوا بعيدا جدا.
Didn't you say there is a class activity going on?
ألم تقل أن هناك نشاطًا دراسيًا جارياً؟
How come it is only a few of you?
كيف يمكن أن يكون عدد قليل منكم فقط؟
It's over much earlier.
لقد انتهى الأمر قبل ذلك بكثير.
What's the problem?
ما هي المشكلة؟
Besides, it was Bai Qijia whom I asked for help.
إلى جانب ذلك ، كان باي قيجيا هو من طلبت المساعدة.
It's none of your business.
هذا ليس من شأنك.
What is the relationship between you two?
ما هي العلاقة بينكما؟
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
Let me tell you.
دعني أخبرك.
Bai Qijia is under my care.
باي Qijia تحت رعايتي.
He's our classmate.
إنه زميلنا في الفصل.
I'm their class monitor.
أنا مراقب الفصل.
So his business is mine.
لذا فإن عمله هو لي.
Stop kidding me.
توقف عن ممازحتي.
Who in our year doesn't know
من في عامنا لا يعرف
that you oppress Bai Qijia the most?
بأنك تضطهد باي قيجيا أكثر من غيرها؟
How could you have the nerve to talk about it?
كيف يمكن أن يكون لديك الجرأة للحديث عن ذلك؟
Let me tell you. Don't you...
دعني أخبرك.  أنت , لا...
Qin Ge is my best friend.
تشين قه هو أعز أصدقائي.
She has never forced me.
هي لم تجبرني ابدا
Please apologize to her.
من فضلك اعتذر لها.
Now.
حاليا.
Asking us to apologize to her?
يطلب منا الاعتذار لها؟
Who do you think you are?
من تظن نفسك؟
It hurts.
هذا مؤلم.
You...
أنت...
Apologize!
يعتذر!
-I'm sorry. -So sorry.
-أنا آسف.  -اسف جدا.
Qin Ge!
تشين قه!
Don't be angry.
لا تغضب.
I accepted their absence.
قبلت غيابهم.
You accepted it, but I didn't.
لقد قبلتها ، لكنني لم أفعل.
Bai Qijia,
باي قيجيا ،
can you please stand up for yourself just once?
هل يمكنك أن تدافع عن نفسك مرة واحدة فقط؟
Can you please have a bottom line?
هل يمكنك الحصول على النتيجة النهائية من فضلك؟
Do you enjoy being a kind person so much?
هل تستمتع بكونك شخصًا لطيفًا كثيرًا؟
How is it?
كيف هذا؟
Let me have a look.
دعني ألقي نظرة.
I... I'm sorry.
أنا ... أنا آسف.
I'm not angry at you.
أنا لست غاضبًا منك.
Okay. I'm indeed...
تمام.  أنا بالفعل ...
I'm angry at you.
انا غاضبة منك.
It's all your fault.
هذا كله خطأك.
Thanks to you,
شكرا لك،
I had to write the reading notes five times.
كان علي أن أكتب ملاحظات القراءة خمس مرات.
I wrote till my hands were numb.
كتبت حتى خدرت يدي.
You must be furious at me
يجب أن تكون غاضبًا مني
for taking revenge on you so blatantly.
للانتقام منك بشكل صارخ.
I'm not furious.
أنا لست غاضبًا.
Really?
هل حقا؟
Bai Qijia,
باي قيجيا ،
have you been like this all along?
هل كنت مثل هذا طوال الوقت؟
Treating others neutrally
معاملة الآخرين بحيادية
having no desire, and acting like a piece of wood?
ليس لديه رغبة ، ويتصرف مثل قطعة من الخشب؟
I'm used to it.
أنا معتاد على ذلك.
Cut the crap.
قطع الفضلات.
Humans should have emotions.
يجب أن يكون لدى البشر عواطف.
Laugh when you're happy.
اضحك عندما تكون سعيدا.
Throw a tantrum when you're unhappy.
قم بإلقاء نوبة غضب عندما تكون غير سعيد.
Say it out when you're dissatisfied.
قلها عندما تكون غير راضٍ.
Don't suppress your emotions.
لا تقمع عواطفك.
You'll get sick easily like that.
سوف تمرض بسهولة من هذا القبيل.
Oh, yes.
نعم بالتأكيد.
This book suits you well.
هذا الكتاب يناسبك جيدًا.
You must learn to say "no."
يجب أن تتعلم أن تقول "لا".
(Refuse. Learn To Say "No")
(رفض. تعلم أن تقول "لا")
Then, can I refuse to be the assistant class monitor?
بعد ذلك ، هل يمكنني رفض أن أكون مراقب الفصل المساعد؟
No way!
مستحيل!
This... This suits you well.
هذا ... هذا يناسبك جيدًا.
(Emotional Equations) Control your emotions,
(المعادلات العاطفية) تحكم في عواطفك ،
and you won't get angry all the time.
ولن تغضب طوال الوقت.
Bai Qijia.
باي قيجيا.
(Malevolence) This book...suits you well.
(الحقد) هذا الكتاب .. يناسبك جيدا.
(Sense and Sensibility) This book suits you well.
(العقل والعاطفة) هذا الكتاب يناسبك جيدًا.
(One Hundred Years of Solitude)
(مائة عام من العزلة) هذا الكتاب يناسبك جيدًا.
(L'etranger) This book suits you well.
(L'etranger) هذا الكتاب يناسبك جيدًا.
Bai Qijia,
باي قيجيا ،
why did you
لماذا فعلت
transfer to this school when the college entrance exam is just around the corner?
الانتقال إلى هذه المدرسة عندما يكون امتحان القبول في الكلية قاب قوسين أو أدنى؟
My parents are busy getting divorced and have no time for me.
والداي مشغولان في الطلاق وليس لديّ وقت لي.
So they sent me here.
لذا أرسلوني إلى هنا.
But it's still the same regardless of where I study.
لكنها لا تزال كما هي بغض النظر عن مكان دراستي.
You don't have to tell me this.
ليس عليك أن تخبرني بهذا.
(﻿The Sleepless Bunny)
(الأرنب الطاهر)
Close your eyes.
اغلق عينيك.
Close them.
أغلقهم.
Look. Does it look like you?
نظرة.  هل يشبهك؟
Look at this rabbit.
انظر إلى هذا الأرنب.
I thought it looked very much like you.
اعتقدت أنها تشبهك كثيرا.
So I drew it.
لذلك رسمتها.
You drew me secretly?
هل رسمتني سرا؟
I didn't do it secretly.
لم أفعل ذلك سرا.
I'm imitating.
أنا أقلد.
What is your motive for imitating?
ما هو دافعك للتقليد؟
Just forget it then.
فقط انسى ذلك الحين.
Why say so much?
لماذا أقول الكثير؟
Wait for a moment.
انتظر لحظة.
Give me the book.
أعطني الكتاب.
The book...belongs to the library.
الكتاب ... ينتمي إلى المكتبة.
You need to return it.
تحتاج إلى إعادته.
Then, draw another piece for me.
ثم ارسم قطعة أخرى من أجلي.
I'll check my schedule.
سوف أتحقق من جدولي الزمني.
The self-study evening session is about to begin. I'll get going then.
الجلسة المسائية للدراسة الذاتية على وشك البدء.  سأذهب بعد ذلك.
You haven't cleared up the books!
لم تقم بمسح الكتب!
(Any plans for the weekend? 1. No; 2. No for now; 3. No, if you say so)
(أي خطط لعطلة نهاية الأسبوع؟ 1. لا ؛ 2. لا الآن ؛ 3. لا ، إذا قلت ذلك)
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
-Sir. -I...
-سيد.  -أنا...
I have a question that I don't understand.
لدي سؤال لا أفهمه.
Come over.
تعال إلى هنا.
For this question, I should choose...
لهذا السؤال ، يجب أن أختار ...
Look here.
انظر هنا.
(No, if you say so.)
(لا ، إذا قلت ذلك).
Look here. For this part, we need to...
انظر هنا.  في هذا الجزء ، نحتاج إلى ...
♪Light shines through window before a mirror♪
يسطع الضوء من خلال النافذة أمام المرآة
♪Incense smoke outlines your appearance♪
دخان البخور يحدد مظهرك ♪
♪Enclosed in the vivid past♪
محاطة بالماضي الزاهي ♪
♪Those miseries which I'm the sole audience♪
♪ تلك المآسي التي أنا الجمهور الوحيد
♪In the imagination of our future♪
في مخيلة مستقبلنا
♪You appear in every scroll♪
تظهر في كل لفة ♪
♪I think I have lost my mind♪
♪ أعتقد أنني فقدت عقلي ♪
♪The world is blooming for you♪
♪ العالم يزهر لك
♪Ignoring the flaws and truths♪
تجاهل العيوب والحقائق
♪With you by my side, I have no fears♪
معكم بجانبي ليس لدي مخاوف ♪
♪Light shines through window before a mirror♪
يسطع الضوء من خلال النافذة أمام المرآة
♪Incense smoke outlines your appearance♪
دخان البخور يحدد مظهرك ♪
♪Enclosed in the vivid past♪
محاطة بالماضي الزاهي ♪
♪Those miseries which I'm the sole audience♪
♪ تلك المآسي التي أنا الجمهور الوحيد
♪In the imagination of our future♪
في مخيلة مستقبلنا
♪You appear in every scroll♪
تظهر في كل لفة ♪
♪I think I have lost my mind♪
♪ أعتقد أنني فقدت عقلي ♪
♪The world is blooming for you♪
♪ العالم يزهر لك
♪Ignoring the flaws and truths♪
تجاهل العيوب والحقائق
♪With you by my side, I have no fears♪
معكم بجانبي ليس لدي مخاوف ♪